Two tiny agents vs. the world's wickedest woman
in a dazzling animated adventure!
The Rescuers is a fantasy, family, animation film
directed by Wolfgang Reitherman.
Two agents of the mouse-run International Rescue Aid Society search for a
little orphan girl kidnapped by sinister treasure hunters.
Bernard (voice), played by Bob Newhart.
Miss Bianca (voice), played by Eva Gabor.
Madame Medusa (voice), played by Geraldine Page.
Mr. Snoops (voice), played by Joe Flynn.
Ellie Mae (voice), played by Jeanette Nolan.
Luke (voice), played by Pat Buttram.
The Rescuers is a 1977 American animated adventure comedy-drama film produced by
Walt Disney Productions and released by Buena Vista Distribution.
Bob Newhart and Eva Gabor respectively star as Bernard and Bianca, two mice who are members of the Rescue Aid
Society, an international mouse organization dedicated to helping abduction victims around the world.
Both must free 6-year-old orphan Penny (voiced by Michelle Stacy) from two treasure hunters (played by
Geraldine Page and Joe Flynn), who intend to use her to help them obtain a giant diamond.
The film is based on a series of books by Margery Sharp,
including The Rescuers (1959) and Miss Bianca (1962).
An early version of The Rescuers entered development in 1962, but was
shelved due to Walt Disney's dislike of its political overtones.
During the 1970s, the film was revived as a project intended for the
younger animators, with the oversight of the senior staff.
Four years were spent on the film's production.
The Rescuers was released on June 22, 1977, to positive critical reception and became a
box office success, earning $48 million during its initial theatrical run.
It has since grossed $169 million after two
theatrical re-releases in 1983 and 1989.
Due to the film's success, a sequel titled The Rescuers Down Under was released in 1990,
which made this the first Disney theatrical animated film to have a sequel.
The film explores themes of rescue, kidnapping, mouse, cartoon, villain.